Looking at different segments of your data can also be useful for
查看数据的各个部分对于评估指标定义
evaluating metric definitions,
也十分有用
since you can look at how the different definitions vary by segment.
因为你能够看到各部分的定义有什么差异
This exploration is useful when building intuition about your data
构建关于数据和系统的直觉时
and your system.
这个探究很有用
For example, let's look at total active cookies over time,
例如 我们看看随着时间的推移总的活跃 cookies
since that's an important high-level business metric.
因为这是一个重要的高级业务指标
So this plot shows the number of active cookies per day for the past four weeks.
这个图展示了过去四周中每天的活跃 cookies 的数量
And there's this weird spike that showed up sometime last week.
这有一个上周某个时间出现的奇怪的高峰
You can also see some weekly variation.
还可以看到一些周间变化
The number of visitors looks higher over the weekend.
看起来周末访客数量更多
One way I can verify whether the spike is odd is by looking
核实这个高峰是否是偶然情况的一个方法是通过查看
at what's called a week-over-week plot.
周周图表
That is, I'll divide each data point by the corresponding data point
也就是说 我用每个数据点除以一周之前
from a week ago.
对应的数据点
As you can see, that tends to smooth out the weekly variation.
正如你所看到的 每周变化平稳
So if I had wondered whether one of these spikes was higher than usual,
因此 如果我想要知道为什么这些高峰中的一个比其他的要高
I can see looking at this plot that it would stand out if one of
我可以看看这个图 如果其中一个在一周中的某天异常高
these were abnormally high given what day of the week it was.
这个高峰就会很显眼
Since we see that this same spike is still here,
因为我们看到这个相同的高峰仍然在这儿
that makes it clear that this spike is not due to weekly variation.
这表明这个高峰不是由于周变化产生的
By the way, this corresponding drop, a week later, happens because we divided
另外 一周之后 会发生相应的下降 因为我们
this data point by the spike that occurred a week earlier.
用这个数据除以一周之前的那个高峰
Another good thing to look at is year-over-year data.
另一个很好的方法是查看年数据
This is the same as week over week, but dividing by the numbers from a year ago.
与周数据一样 但是除以的是一年之前的数据
That way, if there's an annual conference or
这样 如果有年会或
something causing the spike, it will disappear.
产生高峰的事件 它就会消失
But, as you can see, the same spike is still here,
但 可以看到 同一高峰仍然在这里
meaning it's probably not due to a yearly variation.
表明它可能不是由于年变化产生的
You can also see that the weekly variation is back, since the day of week
你还可以回头看看周变化 因为一周中的某天
is not quite matched up to the day of week from a year ago.
和一年前一周中的某天不匹配
Now the question is, if we can pin down what's causing this spike,
现在问题是 如果我们能够确定是什么造成这个高峰
since it doesn't seem to be caused by either weekly or yearly variation.
因为它看起来不像是由于周或年变化产生的
One way we could figure this out is by looking at this metric across
我们确定这个高峰产生原因的一个方法是
different segments of our population to see if one segment is causing the spike.
查看我们群体各部分的这个指标 看看是否是由于某一部分造成了这个高峰
So let's trying looking at how this metric varies by country.
我们看看这个指标是如何随着国家不同而变化的
What's interesting here is that we don't see the spike in most countries, but we
有趣的是在大多数国家中我们看不到高峰
do see it in Berzerkistan, so that one country was causing the entire spike.
但我们在 Berzerkistan 可以看到 因此一个国家造成了整个高峰
At this point, it's a good idea to talk to the engineering team, and
此时 和工程组讨论是一个很好的方法
maybe they'll be able to figure out if this spike is in fact caused
或许他们能够计算出这个高峰是否
by only a small number of rogue IP addresses.
只是由于少量行为异常的 IP 地址引起的
And this is pretty likely to be spam, or a row grow bot, or some competitor
这很像垃圾邮件或 grow bot 或某个竞争对手
trying to get information about classes, or something of that nature.
企图得到关于课程的信息 或此类性质的行为
Now suppose that you suspect there is an issue with JavaScript click tracking.
现在 假设你怀疑 JavaScript 点击跟踪有问题
Specifically, you're worried that JavaScript is counting
特别是 你担心 JavaScript
each click event twice on mobile but not on desktop.
在移动端将每次点击事件记为两次 但对电脑端不计算
Which of the following graphs would confirm this problem if it existed?
以下哪个图表能够确认这个问题是否存在？
First, would a graph of
首先 随时间变化的点击率图表
click-through-rate over time help you find the problem?
能够帮助你找出问题所在吗？
This would be a line graph showing click-through-rate over time.
这是一个表明点击率随时间变化的线图
What about click through probability over time?
点击概率会随时间变化吗？
You can assume the page view definition with a time interval of five minutes.
你可以假设五分钟时间段内网页浏览的定义
This graph would look pretty similar to the first, but
这个图表看起来跟第一个非常相似
showing a probability instead of a rate.
但显示的是概率 而不是比率
Or how about showing both click through rate and probability on the same graph?
或者如何在同一图表上同时显示点击率和点击概率？
So there would be two lines of different colors.
因此 有两种不同颜色的线
Would it help to see click-through-rate over time broken down by platform?
查看具体平台的随时间变化的点击率有帮助吗？
That is, there would be one color of line for mobile and another for desktop.
也就是说 移动端是一种颜色 电脑端是另一种颜色
Or similarly, would it help to see click-through-probability by platform?
或者同样 通过平台查看点击概率有帮助吗？
Finally, what about a graph showing both click through rate and
最后 一个图表显示不同平台的点击率和概率
probability by platform?
会怎样？
That is, show both of the previous two graphs side by side so
也就是说 并列显示两个之前的图表
you can compare them.
这样你可以对它们进行比较
In each case,
针对每种情况
decide whether this visualization by itself could help you decide whether or
确定可视化图表本身 能够帮你确定
not there was a problem, without referencing any of the other graphs.
是否有问题 而无需参考任何其他图表
Thus, click-through-rate, by itself, couldn't tell you whether there was
因此 点击率本身不能帮你判断是否有问题
a problem, since you don't expect the click tracking issue to vary over time.
因为你不希望点击跟踪问题随时间变化
And click-through-probability, by itself, wouldn't tell you much either.
点击概率本身也不会帮你判断
For each of the other four cases, check the box
对于其他四种情况中的每种情况
if you think this comparison would tell you whether or not there was a problem.
如果你认为这个比较结果能够帮你判断是否有问题 在方框中打钩